[
    {
        "question": "...... change is brought through the implementation of such policies.",
        "options": [
            "Social",
            "Economic",
            "Political",
            "Cultural"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Block Development Officer is recruited through ...... examinations held at the state level.",
        "options": [
            "Competitive",
            "Merits",
            "Civil",
            "State"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The ...... are aware of the history of successes and failures of policies.",
        "options": [
            "Council of Ministers",
            "Officers",
            "Civil Servants",
            "Department"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The bureaucracy is politically ......",
        "options": [
            "Alert",
            "Neutral",
            "Expert",
            "Power"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "...... Means that a civil service should not be held directly responsible for any success or failure of policy.",
        "options": [
            "Anonymity",
            "Democratisation",
            "Bureaucracy",
            "Policy"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The ...... has established autonomous institutions like the Public Service Commission for selecting efficient civil servants.",
        "options": [
            "Constitution",
            "Council of Ministers",
            "Parliament",
            "President"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The system of ...... is also known as bureaucracy.",
        "options": [
            "UPSC",
            "MPCS",
            "Civil Servants"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The ...... selects candidates through competitive examinations and recommends them to the government to be recruited in the state administration.",
        "options": [
            "UPSC",
            "MPSC"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The parliament holds the Minister responsible for ......",
        "options": [
            "Misbehaving",
            "Malpractices",
            "Development",
            "Bureaucracy"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bureaucracy also plays an important role in the ...... of society.",
        "options": [
            "Progressive",
            "Implementation",
            "Democratisation",
            "Anonymity"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The functions of government are discharged by various ......",
        "options": [
            "Scheme",
            "Department",
            "Policy",
            "Political"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Marginalised sections of society have been brought into mainstream by implementing the ...... policy.",
        "options": [
            "Progressive",
            "Reservation",
            "Effective",
            "Development"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The new government may change some ...... of the earlier government.",
        "options": [
            "Polices",
            "Aware",
            "Scheme",
            "Anonymity"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian Foreign Service is included under ......",
        "options": [
            "All India Services",
            "Union or Central Service",
            "State Civil Service",
            "Armed Forces"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "There are ...... servants in the government administrative system.",
        "options": [
            "State",
            "Central",
            "Civil",
            "Union"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The parliament holds the ...... responsible for malpractices.",
        "options": [
            "Bureaucracy",
            "Prime minister",
            "Minister",
            "President"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The ...... of the department gives expert advice to the Ministers.",
        "options": [
            "Secretary",
            "Minister",
            "Service",
            "Commission"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The aspirations of the people and administrative expertise are thus put in ...... in the parliamentary system.",
        "options": [
            "Peace",
            "Harmony",
            "Centre",
            "Service"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In parliamentary ...... representatives elected by the people and the ministers have the responsibility of administration.",
        "options": [
            "Republic",
            "Democracy",
            "Central",
            "State"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The role of ...... security is carried out an aid to civil authority.",
        "options": [
            "External",
            "Internal"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The Prime Minister and their council of Ministers change after every ......",
        "options": [
            "Elections",
            "Five years",
            "Policy",
            "Scheme"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "...... is the administrative system which works under the Union Executive and has the responsibility of actual implementation of governments policies.",
        "options": [
            "Impeachment",
            "Bureaucracy"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Bureaucracy gives stability to the ...... system.",
        "options": [
            "Political",
            "Dual",
            "Central",
            "State"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
]